Ronald B. Dekker

PhD Student in Cognitive Neuroscience

Linton Road 31-110, OX2 6UL, Oxford, United Kingdom Email: ronald976@gmail.com | Website: ronald976.github.io Tel: +31 657588768

PROFILE

I am a motivated cognitive computational neuroscience researcher with a wide range of academic interests. This is reflected by my PhD work, which combines analysis of artificial learning systems, computational modeling of behavior and analysis of real neural data. It is my firm belief that an interdisciplinary approach can provide insights unobtainable by the pursuit of any individual field.

Research interests: representation learning, training curricula, continual learning, decision making, computational modelling, artificial intelligence, neurolinguistics, visual perception, methodology

EDUCATION

2017 - Present University of Oxford

PhD in Experimental Psychology

Supervised by Dr. Christopher Summerfield

Funding: Wolfson Marriott Graduate Scholarship in Experimental

Psychology and MSD CSEF grant

Project 1: Internal noise as a determinant of curriculum efficacy (in prep.)

Project 2: Capacity limits place constraints on human information integration

Project 3: Compositional learning in humans and machines

2010 - 2017 University of Amsterdam

MSc in Brain & Cognitive Sciences (cum laude), GPA: 9.0/10

BSc in Psychobiology (with honours) BSc in Interdisciplinary Sciences

EXPERIENCE

2019-2019 Teaching at University of Oxford

Demonstrated and graded for undergraduate courses

2018-2020 Student supervision at University of Oxford

Supervised 3 students' research projects (1 year each)

- EEG correlates of boundary-distal versus boundary-proximal training schemes (Eleanor Holton)
- Curriculum effects in the weather prediction task (Fabian Otto)
- Decision-making biases account for discrepancies between empirical behavior and formal models of probabilistic evidence integration (Mingfang Zhang)

2017-2017 Tesla Minor

Consultancy project for healthcare innovation company ActiveCues

- Assessed feasibility of creating a new product for 50 psychopathological groups
- Brought together researchers, developers and clinicians to bring a scientific framework into practice
- Developed a serious game to tackle substance abuse using interactive light projections

2015-2017 Editor at ABC (Amsterdam Brain and Cognition) journal

Reviewed submitted articles and adapted these to a publishable format with Adobe InDesign

PUBLICATIONS AND PRESENTATIONS

Publications Dekker, R., Holton, E., Flesch, T., Saxe, A. & Summerfield, C.

(2021). Internal noise as a determinant of curriculum efficacy

(in prep.)

Flesch, T., Balaguer, J., Dekker, R., Nili, H. & Summerfield, C. (2018). Comparing continual task learning in minds and machines. *Proceedings of the*

National Academy of Sciences

Presentations Schulz and Schuck lab (Max Planck Institutes, Tuebingen & Berlin) - Joint

lab meeting (March 2021). Title: compositional learning in humans and

machines

Orban lab (MTA Wigner Research Centre, Budapest) - Lab meeting (July 2020). Title: Hierarchical composition through B-VAE latents

International Symposium on Biology of Decision Making (2018)

& 2019). Poster presentations

Department of Experimental Psychology (University of Oxford) - Departmental seminar (Dec 2019). Title: Curriculum learning

QUALIFICATIONS

Technical skills Python, MATLAB, JavaScript, HTML, UNIX (Ubuntu), Excel, SPSS, R,

(ordered by proficiency) DOS, FSL, Wolfram Mathematica

Research techniques Artificial neural networks (PyTorch, TensorFlow), EEG, disciplinary and

interdisciplinary collaboration, experimental design, computational

modelling & model comparison, statistics

Languages Dutch: Fluent (native)

English: Fluent - BLTC (British Language Training Centre) Academic

English grade: 8.5 (tested 2011)

Japanese: Intermediate - OULC (Oxford University Langage Centre) CEFR

B1 level certificate available (June 2020)